Jeremy Springman

Research Assistant Professor University of Pennsylvania ☑: jspr@sas.upenn.edu ☐: jrspringman.github.io ♠: https://github.com/jrspringman

I am an applied researcher working to design, implement, and evaluate data-driven solutions to complex problems. I have deep experience managing highly interdisciplinary research teams, establishing long-term collaborations with public and private sector partners, and communicating technical material to policy audiences. I have six years of experience managing a team of 12 researchers and staff in a lab environment and 10 years of experience with causal inference and machine learning research tools. Since 2022, I have been awarded nearly \$3.5 million as a principal investigator on both federal and private research grants.

Work Experience

University of Pennsylvania, PDRI-DevLab

Research Assistant Professor Senior Research Associate & Director of Research July 2024 – Present July 2022 – June 2024

- Led development of large-scale webscraping and ML text classification pipeline to track and forecast political events and instability around the world
- Deployed public-facing data dashboards and early warning system to inform crisis response and policy planning (150 hours of monthly usage; 800 newsletter sign-ups)
- Designed and analyzed randomized experiments to measure program success
- Developed course on causal inference and data science; advised students

Duke University, DevLab@Duke

Senior Research Associate

July 2021 – June 2022

Post-Doctoral Research Associate

July 2021 – June 2021

January 2019 – June 2021

Education

University of Pennsylvania Ph.D. in Comparative Politics & International Relations M.A. in Political Science 2015 University of Pittsburgh B.A. in Politics & Philosophy (Honors College) 2012

Selected External Awards & Grants

My research has been supported by the U.S. Department of Defense, Agency for International Development, and National Science Foundation and multiple private foundations. Since 2022, I have been a principal investigator on nearly \$3.5 million in awards, carrying projects from conceptualization and proposal through design, implementation, and the dissemination of results to the scientific and policy communities. My most recent awards include:

- \$1.6m Department of Defense Minerva Research Initiative grant to support interdisciplinary research with Environmental Sciences faculty to model the impact of climate change on adaptation, conflict, and migration.
- \$900,000 Agency for International Development grant to develop large-scale webscraping and machine learning text classification pipeline tracking and forecasting foreign influence operations and political instability in aid-receiving countries

Invited Public Speaking

I am passionate about communicating research findings for non-technical audiences to inform decision-making. My recent public speaking invitations include:

- U.S. Department of State (Washington, D.C.): I presented results from a commissioned trial applying novel data produced by my research team to forecast political instability. The focus was on how forecasts should inform DoS budget and operations planning.
- Perry World House (Philadelphia): I discussed how my research can shape decision-makers' understanding of Russia's foreign policy and influence operations in developing countries.
- Leibniz Center for Informatics (Germany): I discussed the use of ML/AI to extract information from highly-multilingual text for a continuous, large-scale data production operation.
- U.S. Army (Fort Liberty), UN Data Strategy Community (remote), Vienna University of Economics and Business (Austria): I introduced public-facing data products developed by my team to track political events and forecast instability in emerging markets. Discussion focused on the use of event tracking and forecast data dashboards for decision-making.

Refereed Academic Publications

The Political Economy of NGO Service Provision: Evidence from an Ancillary Field Experiment World Politics, 2022 (DOI: S0043887122000107)

The Effect of Government Repression on Civil Society: Evidence from Cambodia International Studies Quarterly, 2022 (DOI: sqac028)
First author (with Edmund Malesky, Lucy Right, and Erik Wibbels)

Oil Discoveries and Political Windfalls: Evidence on Presidential Support in Uganda Political Science Research & Methods, 2023 (DOI: psrm.2023.14) Second author (with Laura Paler, Guy Grossman, and Jan Pierskalla)

Academic Manuscripts Under Review

I have six academic manuscripts currently under review (including revise & resubmit) at academic journals. The projects use causal inference and ML tools applied to spatial, network, financial, and text data. Specific topics include an RCT to expand youth social networks and civic engagement in Ethiopia, experimental research on organization decision-making in autocracies, and the strategic logic of Russian influence operations.

Selected Policy Reports in 2024 (contact for full list)

High Frequency Tracking of Civic Space Utilizing Domestic News Scraping and LLM Classification Prepared for Swift Expertise and Grounded Analytics Task Order by USAID DRG Bureau

Forecasting High-Level Travel Advisories with Machine Learning for Peace Data Prepared for Swift Expertise and Grounded Analytics Task Order by USAID DRG Bureau

Charting a Course for Applied Research in Peacebuilding Published by United States Institute of Peace

Report of the Advisory Panel for the Governance of Human Rights Organizations Convened for Amnesty International by Dr. Hazar Yueksel (SocArXiv DOI: 10.31235)